Ketan Badhe

Dublin, Ireland

badhe.ketan@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/ketanbadhe/ https://ketanbb69.github.io/

Profile:

A Cloud Computing student, who has worked on multiple computer programming technologies for the last three years. I am well-versed in AWS, the Linux operating system, Bash programming, and Python. When working with past organizations, I have worked on a variety of DevOps technologies and am well-versed in CI/CD. Actively researching deep learning inference utilizing AWS tools. To supplement my masters, I work part-time at a Multi-National IT Company in Ireland. Independent and self-motivated, with a track record of learning new technologies rapidly and going the additional mile to help others.

Visa: Current status: Stamp 2. Anticipate completing Masters program by September 2022.

Languages: English (Fluent – oral & written), Marathi (Native), Hindi.

Technology Skills:

- Python, C: Using Python and C for 4+ years and achieved first-class results in all of the modules throughout the degree.
- Shell Script: Exercised shell scripting knowledge to automate the tasks while working for Amdocs.
- **Operating Systems:** Gained in-depth knowledge of operating systems and administered Linux-based systems and windows systems including server operating systems.
- Cloud IaaS & SaaS Platforms: Deployed web applications and addressed certain DevOps procedures on AWS EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, and CodeDeploy. Experience with services like CodeCommit, IAM, CloudWatch Alarms, and CodePipeline.
- Middleware and other tools: Dealt with WebLogic as middleware in the workplace. Also utilized Jenkins for CI/CD approach and hands-on experience on Kubernetes.

Education:

Masters in Cloud Computing | National College of Ireland, Dublin

September 2021 - August 2022

- Research in Computing: Selected topic for Research Thesis "Traversing Serverless Computing with Elastic File System to Deploy Large Deep Learning Model for Inference."
- Modules: Cloud Architecture, Cloud DevOpsSec, Cloud Platform Programming, Blockchain Concepts, Fog and Edge Computing, Cloud Machine Learning, and Scalable Cloud Programming.

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science | University of Mumbai

June 2014 - June 2018

- **Final year project:** PREDICTION OF USERS' PERFORMANCE ON A MARKETING WEBSITE.(<u>.pdf</u>) Calculated the exact sales and prices of most sold items using the SPADE Algorithm and predicted a sale by ID3 Algorithm.
- Modules: Cloud Computing, Data Warehouse and Mining, Parallel and Distributed Systems, Software Engineering, Digital Forensic, Microprocessors, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Mobile Computing, Distributed Databases, Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming.

Projects:

- 3AK Pharma An Integrated Cloud-Based Health Care Solution | April 2022: Implemented an online doctor consultation, pharmacist and pathology lab integrated web-based system. The web application makes use of a publicly available REST API named Auth0 for authentication and a self-developed API for access management. Deployed the web application on Amazon Web services AWS Beanstalk platform and have also provisioned a full life-cycle CICD pipeline for the purpose of quick delivery and deployment of changes.
- SARS-CoV-2 Pandemic Analysis and Prediction using Cloud-based Machine Learning Models | April 2022: Devised several algorithms such as Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM), Prophet Model, and Pattern Evaluation to accurately forecast the future of the pandemic. The project displays the data in form of graphs and charts making it more meaningful and understandable.
- Stock Investment Tool for Cloud Platform Programming | December 2021: Focused on the application to perform the trading activities such as obtaining and selling the manually created one or more lists of shares and seeing the portfolio. Along with that, analyze the portfolio balance with other users.
- Stock Portfolio Management | December 2021: Designed an application (Stock Portfolio Management) to provide users with real-time stock information of any number of shares, used for acquiring and selling shares, and hosted the application in Amazon Web Services Cloud.
- Smart Contract Deployment in Blockchain | December 2021: Implemented the smart contract containing an ERC20 compliant ethereum token using node js JavaScript framework. The docker image is created and distributed 5% of the total supply of a token.
- Users' behaviour prediction in e-commerce website | March 2018: Calculated the actual sales and prices of most sold items using the SPADE Algorithm and predicted a sale by the ID3 Algorithm. A set of descriptive data mining techniques is applied that allows data analysts working at e-commerce companies to make strategic decisions to boost their sales as well as provide adequate customer service.

Work Experience:

Amdocs, India | Technology Integration Engineer

September 2018 – August 2021

- Operated multitudinous DevOps tools such as Jenkins, and Kubernetes for the deployment and daily activities such as maintenance window to shut down and start-up up the application. Provided support during cloud migration.
- Applied scripting knowledge to find out the number of configuration mistakes easily, kept an eye on every server for utilization, and improve time complexity.
- Experienced in BOT Automation, operated for configuration and validation purposes, as a reason the team does not need to do the configuration and validations manually.
- Provided support to the numerous applications at the same time to maintain all the applications keep running without any problems and ensure health.
- Built the non-productive and production-like environments likewise configured to the latest versions.
- Fixed the emergency fixes in the application and on a middle-ware such as WebLogic (an Oracle product).

SAP, Ireland | IT SERVICE DESK AGENT (PART-TIME)

January 2022 - Current

- Ensuring the IT Incidents and Service Requests are resolved within a given SLA.
- Applying solutions, workarounds, patches and fixes.
- first point of contact for SAP customers on SAP Community Network application.
- Highlighting all potential major incidents and problems to the respective service and problem managers.

Certifications:

Operate Kubernetes on IBM cloud (IBM) | <u>Credentials</u>
Learn DevOps: CI/CD with Jenkins pipeline and Docker (Udemy) | <u>Credentials</u>
Ultimate AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (Udemy) | <u>Credentials</u>

Hobbies:

- Analyzing stock charts using technical analysis, devising new workable technical strategies, and carrying out trading activities.
- Playing and watching Cricket and Kabaddi. When playing for the College team and the Corporate squad, I represented and earned leadership in both sports.